Thank you very much!
Terima kasih banyak!
Next, we'll be performing a song with a lot of beat.
Selanjutnya, kami mainkan lagu yang seru.
"Everlasting Luv"!
"Cinta Abadi"!
Love is eternal. Labyrinths are mysterious.
Cinta itu abadi. Labirin itu misterius.
Saturday nights are for mystery.
Sabtu malam penuh misteri.
Solve the locked dressing room trick
Pecahkan trik ruang ganti
and disclose the mixing noise in the band.
dan bongkar suara dalam band!
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan.
Namanya Detektif Conan.
"Yukiko Watanbe (24), Vocalist"
"Yukiko Watanbe (24), Vokalis."
"Makoto Nishimoto (25), Guitarist"
"Makoto Nishimoto (25), Gitar."
"Shota Aoki (27), Bass Player"
"Shota Aoki (27), Bass."
"Risako Tanaka (22), Keyboard Player"
"Risako Tanaka (22), Piano."
"Yusuke Nakamura (30), Drummist"
"Yusuke Nakamura (30), Drum."
"Yuuki Sakamoto (38), Music Producer"
"Yuuki Sakamoto (38), Produser Musik."
Conan, eat to your heart's content. No need to hold back!
Conan, makanlah. Jangan malu-malu!
Don't worry about a thing! It's my treat!
Jangan khawatir! Aku yang traktir!
I can have anything I like? But all there is here are soy beans, sausage
Ada yang aku suka? Tapi yang ada cuma kedelai, sosis,
and finger food you eat with alcoholic drinks.
dan cemilan yang dimakan bersama alkohol.
What's wrong? Soy beans and sausages for dinner.
Ada apa? Makan malam kedelai dan sosis.
Isn't it great?
Bagus kan?
One more glass of beer!
Bir satu gelas lagi!
Dad, don't drink too much.
Ayah, jangan minum terlalu banyak.
What are you talking about?
Apa yang kau bicarakan?
I wasted half a day shopping with you since you wanted to buy clothes.
Aku belanja seharian karena kau mau beli baju.
Stop nagging me about drinking beer.
Jangan ganggu aku minum bir.
But still...
Tapi...
I don't know any of the songs.
Aku tidak tahu banyak lagu.
We'll play something different now.
Kami mainkan sesuatu yang berbeda.
It's a song that I'm sure you've all heard.
Lagu yang kalian semua tahu.
Play Yoko Okino's "Moon Lady"!
Mainkan "Moon Lady" dari Yoko Okino!
Don't tell me you can't play it!
Jangan bilang kau tak bisa memainkannya!
Hey, dad!
Hei, ayah!
I'm going to the washroom.
Aku ke toilet.
Next, we'd like to play S&G's masterpiece for you.
Kami akan mainkan karya dari S&G.
They can't play Yoko's song.
Mereka tidak bisa memainkan lagu Yoko.
"8th Floor"
"Lantai 8."
Drawings?
Lukisan?
We had to draw in class the other day.
Kami menggambar di kelas waktu itu.
It wasn't easy trying to draw like a kid.
Tidak mudah menggambar seperti anak-anak.
Excuse me. I'm sorry if I'm mistaken.
Maaf jika aku salah.
Are you the famed Detective Kogoro Mouri?
Kau Detektif Kogoro Mouri terkenal itu?
I am indeed Detective Kogoro Mouri.
Ya, akulah Detektif Kogoro Mouri.
Just as I thought!
Sudah kuduga!
Since you were saying, "Play Yoko Okino's song",
Karena kau bilang, "Mainkan lagu Yoko",
I thought that it could be you.
aku rasa itu kau.
I saw you on air together with her.
Aku lihat kau on air dengannya.
My name is Yusuke Nakamura.
Namaku Yusuke Nakamura.
You saw me on television?
Kau melihatku di TV?
Hey, give me two glasses of beer!
Hei, dua gelas bir!
No thanks.
Tidak, terima kasih.
I just thought that if you were him in person,
Aku cuma pikir jika kau orangnya,
I'd like to have your autograph here.
aku inginkan tanda tanganmu.
No need to be hesitant.
Jangan sungkan-sungkan.
Hey, Conan. Go and buy more snacks!
Hei, Conan. Beli cemilan lagi.
Okay.
Oke.
You want my autograph? No problem.
Oh, tanda tanganku? Tentu.
"Stem beans and popcorn, Fried potato, Fried chicken, French sausage"
"Kacang dan popcorn, Kentang goreng, Ayam goreng, Sosis."
I'm sick of all these food already.
Aku muak dengan makanan ini.
Huh? Where's Ran?
Huh? Dimana Ran?
The guy just now seems to have the CD
Pria itu punya CD
that Ran's been looking for since some time ago,
yang dicari Ran sebelumnya,
so she followed him to the dressing room to borrow it.
jadi dia mengikutinya ke sana untuk pinjam itu.
I see.
Aku mengerti.
"Basement, 1st floor"
"Basement, Lantai 1."
Is the dressing room still open?
Apa ruang gantinya masih buka?
No, the key has been returned.
Tidak, kuncinya sudah dikembalikan.
Here.
Ini.
"Dressing Room, Non-personnel Are Prohibited"
"Ruang Ganti, Bukan Anggota Dilarang Masuk."
I'm sorry, but could you wait for a while here?
Maaf, maukah kau menungguku sebentar?
Sure.
Tentu.
So this is how the musical instruments are stored away.
Jadi, alat musik disimpan seperti ini.
Huh? What's this?
Huh? Apa ini?
Somebody!
Seseorang!
What's the matter?
Ada apa?
That...
Itu...
I flipped that blanket over...
Aku buka selimutnya...
and found Yukiko...
dan aku temukan Yukiko...
She seems to be dead.
Sepertinya dia sudah tewas!
Hurry and get Mr. Mouri!
Cepat panggil Pak Mouri!
Okay!
Oke!
A person was found dead?
Ada orang yang tewas?
Mr. Mouri.
Pak Mouri.
Yukiko is...
Yukiko...
She has been choked to death.
Dia dicekik hingga tewas.
Ran, call the police!
Ran, panggil polisi!
Okay.
Oke.
This is...
Ini...
What is it?
Apa?
So the band members are the victim, Ms. Yukiko Watanabe,
Anggota bandnya ada Nn. Yukiko Watanabe,
you and three other people?
kau dan tiga orang di sampingmu?
-Yes, sir. -Inspector.
-Benar, pak. -Inspektur.
According to the security guard,
Berdasarkan keterangan petugas keamanan,
the only people who borrowed the key to this room
orang yang meminjam kunci ruang ganti
are the members of the band.
hanyalah anggota band ini sahaja.
Mr. Nakamura.
Pak Nakamura.
Could you contact the other three members
Kau bisa hubungi anggota band yang lain
and ask them to come back to the department store?
dan suruh mereka kembali ke mall?
Yes, sir.
Baik, pak.
Excuse me. There are green stains
Maaf. Di kedua pundak Yukiko
on both shoulders of Ms. Yukiko.
ada bercak hijau.
Yeah.
Iya.
Inspector, there is something around her shoulders.
Inspektur, ada sesuatu di area pundaknya.
Please go and check what it is right away.
Segera periksa apa itu sebenarnya.
Yes, sir.
Siap, pak.
What's wrong?
Ada apa?
I can't help feeling that it looks different from when I first saw it.
Aku merasa itu terlihat berbeda berbanding waktu sebelumnya.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
I don't really know.
Aku tidak yakin.
The performance at the beer garden on the roof ended at 8.30 pm.
Acara yang berlangsung di atap tadi selesai pukul 8.30 malam.
Ms. Yukiko's dead body was found at around 9.15 pm.
Jasad Yukiko ditemukan sekitar 9.15 malam.
Will you each tell me what you were doing at that time?
Apa saja yang kalian lakukan saat itu?
I'd like to also know when you all last met Ms. Yukiko.
Aku ingin ketahui kapan terakhir kali kalian bertemu Yukiko.
After I left the stage, I went to the dressing room
Setelah acara, aku mengemas alat-alat musik
to store the instruments with the department store staff.
bersama staf mall di ruang ganti.
About 20 minutes later, I went to Mr. Mouri's table
20 menit kemudian, aku ke meja Pak Mouri
and talked to him for about 15 minutes.
dan mengobrol selama 15 menit.
Then, I went to the dressing room with Ran.
Lalu, aku ke ruang ganti bersama Ran.
The last time I saw Yukiko
Aku bertemu Yukiko
was when she came down from the stage and left.
saat turun panggung sebelum dia pergi.
What about the rest of you?
Bagaimana dengan kalian?
I used the elevator to go down to the dressing room
Aku naik lift dan turun
together with Shota and Makoto,
bersama Shota dan Makoto,
and left for home with Shota about 5 minutes later.
lalu pulang dengan Shota 5 menit kemudian.
According to the security guard's log, it was at 8.40 pm.
Menurut catatan petugas, saat itu pukul 8.40 malam.
The last I saw Yukiko was in front of the elevator.
Aku terakhir melihat Yukiko di hadapan lift.
Go on without me.
Duluan saja.
That's what she said.
Itu yang dia katakan.
Me, too.
Aku juga.
Same here.
Aku pun begitu.
What did you do after you left the department store?
Apa yang kau lakukan setelah pergi dari mall?
Since Shota said he had something to do,
Karena Shota bilang ada urusan,
we parted right outside the department store.
kami berpisah di luar mall.
What about you, Mr. Nishimoto?
Dan kau, Pak Nishimoto?
About 5 minutes after they both left,
5 menit setelah mereka pergi,
I returned the dressing room's key to the security guard and went home.
aku kembalikan kunci ruang ganti lalu pulang.
The log says the key was returned at 8.45 pm.
Menurut catatan, kunci dikembalikan pukul 8.45 malam.
What about you, Mr. Aoki?
Bagaimana denganmu, Pak Aoki?
I waited for Yukiko for some time
Aku menunggu Yukiko sebentar
in the car parked in the parking lot.
di kereta di parkiran.
Why were you waiting for Yukiko?
Bagaimana bisa kau menunggu Yukiko?
I thought you were dating with Risako.
Aku kira kau berpacaran dengan Risako.
I wasn't dating Yukiko.
Aku tidak berpacaran dengan Yukiko.
Then, why were you with Yukiko yesterday?
Lalu, mengapa kau bersama Yukiko kemarin?
You told me you were busy!
Kau bilang kau sibuk!
So, you were seeing Yukiko after all!
Tapi, tetap saja kau bertemu Yukiko!
Cut it out. This isn't the place to talk about it.
Cukup. Ini bukan waktunya untuk membahas itu.
Before Mr. Nakamura and Ran came to borrow the dressing room's key,
Sebelum Pak Nakamura dan Ran pinjam kunci ruang ganti,
someone else came at 8.55 pm to borrow the key.
ada yang datang pinjam kunci pada pukul 8.55 malam.
Mr. Shota Aoki.
Pak Shota Aoki.
It was you, wasn't it?
Itu kau, bukan?
Yes.
Benar, pak.
Shota, don't tell me...
Shota, jangan-jangan kau...
No.
Tidak.
Yukiko didn't show up for a while, so I went to check the dressing room.
Yukiko tidak muncul, jadi aku pergi mencarinya di sana.
But she wasn't there.
Tapi dia tidak ada di ruang ganti.
I waited for a while, but she didn't come.
Biarpun aku menunggu, dia tidak datang.
So I had no choice but to return the key and left for home.
Jadi aku pun kembalikan kunci dan pulang.
It was when the department staff were storing the musical instruments.
Itu adalah saat staf meletakkan alat musik.
The security guard did say that the key was returned in about 5 minutes.
Itu benar kuncinya dikembalikan dalam 5 menit.
By the way, why were you waiting
Mengapa kau menunggu
for the victim, Ms. Yukiko Watanabe?
korban, iaitu Nn. Yukiko Watanabe?
From what you told us,
Dari apa yang kau bilang,
it seems that you two weren't dating each other either.
kalian tidak berpacaran.
Yukiko and I were invited to join another band.
Aku dan Yukiko mendapat undangan dari band lain.
What?
Apa?
We were asked by TMS Record
TMS Record menawarkan kami
if we wanted to make a major debut with that band.
untuk berdebut bersama band itu.
Is... Is that so?
Oh, jadi begitu?
What's this mark?
Apa-apaan ini?
Inspector.
Inspektur.
I've checked the footage of the surveillance camera in the elevator.
Aku telah memeriksa kamera pengawas di lift.
There isn't any footage showing Ms. Yukiko
Tidak ada gambaran yang menunjukkan
going from the roof to the basement.
bahwa Nn. Yukiko pernah menaiki lift ke basement.
What?
Apa?
Are you saying that Ms. Yukiko used the stairs
Maksudmu, Yukiko menggunakan tangga
to go from the roof to the basement, then?
untuk turun ke basement?
That's possible.
Bisa jadi.
What makes you think so?
Apa yang membuatmu berpikir begitu?
Mr. Sakamoto from TMS Record was at the beer garden tonight.
Pak Sakamoto dari TMS Record datang ke acara malam ini.
Mr. Sakamoto walked towards the stairs
Dia menuju ke tangga
when we were taking the elevator.
saat kami naiki lift.
Could you please get in contact with that Mr. Sakamoto?
Bisakah kau tolong hubungi Pak Sakamoto?
Yes, sir.
Siap, pak.
Yes. After the performance ended,
Iya. Saat pertunjukan selesai,
I did see Yukiko at the landing between the roof and 8th floor.
aku bertemu dengan Yukiko di tangga ke lantai 8.
You killed Yukiko!
Kau membunuh Yukiko!
No! I...
Tidak! Aku...
told her how I felt about her performance and left right afterwards.
bilang soal pertunjukannya lalu pergi.
She said she didn't want the other members to see me with her.
Itu karena dia tak mau yang lain melihat aku bersamanya.
Liar!
Bohong!
He's not the one who did it.
Bukan dia yang melakukannya.
Neither he nor Yukiko had the key to the dressing room,
Bukan dia atau Yukiko yang pegang kunci,
so they couldn't have gotten in.
jadi mereka tak bisa masuk ke dalam ruang ganti.
You're getting so worked up.
Kau terlihat kesal sekali.
Makoto, aren't you the one who killed Yukiko?
Makoto, bukannya kau yang bunuh Yukiko?
-What? -I already know
-Apa? -Aku tahu.
that Yukiko brushed you off.
Yukiko mencampakkanmu.
I bet Yukiko came back before you returned the key, right?
Yukiko kembali sebelum kau berikan kunci, kan?
And that's when you...
Dan itulah saat kau...
According to Shota, when he came back from the dressing room,
Shota bilang ruang ganti kosong
there was nobody there, right?
saat dia kembali dari situ, kan?
You were the one who had the key all afternoon, weren't you?
Kau yang bawa kunci siang ini, bukan?
Maybe you made a spare key back then?
Mungkin saja kau duplikat kuncinya?
Don't be ridiculous!
Jangan konyol!
You thought that Yukiko took Shota away from you, right?
Kau pikir Yukiko merebut Shota darimu, kan?
Stop, everyone!
Cukup!
It's a shame to be fighting among ourselves!
Berkelahi sesama sendiri itu tak baik!
If we straighten the story out, it should be like this.
Jadi, jika kita susunkan, ceritanya begini.
Ms. Yukiko who parted with Mr. Sakamoto
Setelah pertemuan dengan Pak Sakamoto,
took the stairs and returned to the dressing room on Floor B1.
Yukiko menggunakan tangga dan kembali ke ruang ganti di lantai B1.
But since she didn't have the key,
Tapi dia tidak pegang kunci,
the killer had to be the one who unlocked the door to the dressing room.
jadi itu bermakna pembunuhnya yang membuka pintu ruang ganti.
So it's either Mr. Nishimoto, before he returned the key,
Itu mungkin adalah Pak Nishimoto sebelum dia kembalikan kunci,
Mr. Aoki who went back there once
Pak Aoki yang pernah kembali ke sana
or Ms. Ritsuko who could've secretly made a spare key.
atau Nn. Ritsuko yang berkesempatan untuk menduplikat kunci.
The killer is among the three of you.
Pembunuhnya ada di antara kalian.
The landing of the stairs between the roof and 8th floor...
Tangga antara atap dan lantai 8...
Yukiko was talking to Mr. Sakamoto over here.
Yukiko bicara dengan Pak Sakamoto di sana.
After that, Yukiko took the stairs all the way down to B1.
Lalu, Yukiko turun tangga ke B1.
Why didn't she use the elevator?
Mengapa dia tidak menggunakan lift?
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
I came all the way here while being lost in thought.
Aku berjalan ke sini tanpa sadarinya.
This drawing... Could it be...
Lukisan ini... Mungkinkah ini...
Is this it?
Mungkinkah ini klu?
Could I be wrong?
Atau bukan?
Kid, what are you doing here?
Nak, apa yang kau lakukan?
It's nothing.
Tidak, tidak ada apa-apa.
Come to think of it, the security guard's room is just nearby.
Soal itu, petugas keamanan ada di dekat sini.
Yet, why did Ran...
Tapi, kenapa Ran...
Ran!
Ran!
Conan.
Conan.
When you saw Ms. Yukiko's body,
Saat kau temukan mayat korban,
why did you come all the way to the roof to get us
kenapa kau menuju ke atap untuk mencari kami
instead of calling the security guard room that's close by?
dan bukannya ke ruang keamanan di dekat sini?
Because Mr. Nakamura told me to go and get Mr. Mouri.
Karena Pak Nakamura bilang cari Pak Mouri.
Oh, right. Conan.
Oh, iya. Conan.
I realized something strange.
Ada sesuatu yang aneh.
The big drum.
Drum besar ini.
When I first saw it, the drum was on top of this case.
Tadi, drumnya ada di atas kotak ini.
But now it's gone.
Tapi sekarang tidak ada.
I see.
Aku mengerti.
Mr. Tome.
Pak Tome.
About the green stuff that was on Ms. Yukiko's shoulders...
Yang hijau di pundak Nn. Yukiko...
That's right. It's amazing you figured it out.
Benar. Hebat kau mengetahuinya.
All right. Everything's fallen into place now.
Baiklah. Semuanya sudah jelas.
That's the killer.
Dialah pelakunya.
Okay, everyone.
Oke, semua.
I need you all to tell me the details at the station.
Kalian harus jelaskan semua di kantor.
No way. Do I have to go too?
Tidak. Maksudmu, aku juga?
I didn't kill her!
Aku tidak membunuhnya!
Mouri!
Mouri!
Don't tell me... Is this position...
Jangan bilang... Posisi itu adalah...
Yes. It's nearing nightfall,
Ya. Ini menjelang malam,
so it's about time we end all this
jadi tiba waktunya kita selesaikan ini
and solve this case.
dan pecahkan kasus ini.
Inspector, Conan was told by the forensic officer
Inspektur, petugas forensik bilang sama Conan
that the green thing on the victim's shoulders was crayon.
bahwa yang hijau di pundak korban itu adalah krayon.
Crayon?
Krayon?
I wonder where it got onto her.
Bagaimana bisa itu ada padanya?
There are no crayons in the dressing room.
Tidak ada krayon di dalam ruang ganti.
Where on earth could it be?
Bagaimana itu bisa terjadi?
It's the 8th floor.
Ia ada di lantai 8.
The 8th floor?
Lantai 8?
Children's drawings are exhibited on the 8th floor.
Lukisan anak-anak dipamerkan di lantai 8.
According to Conan,
Conan bilang,
there seems to be a scrape mark on one of the drawings.
ada goresan pada salah satu gambar.
I'm sure that Ms. Yukiko was attacked on the 8th floor.
Aku yakin Yukiko diserang di lantai 8.
She was probably pushed against the drawing then,
Mungkin saja dia didorong ke arah lukisan
and that's when the crayon scraped off onto her clothes.
dan bajunya tergores krayon.
-What? -In other words,
-Apa? -Dalam arti kata lain,
she wasn't killed in the dressing room, but on the 8th floor.
dia tidak tewas di sini, tapi di lantai 8.
But the body was found in the dressing room.
Tapi, jasadnya ditemukan di ruang ganti.
Her body was moved there.
Ia dibawa kemari.
Officer Takagi.
Petugas Takagi.
Was there a rectangular mark near her neck?
Apa itu tanda kotak di lehernya?
Yes, there was.
Iya, benar.
Dad, I brought it with me.
Ayah, aku sudah membawakannya.
What's that?
Apa itu?
The case for the bass drum.
Kotak drum bass.
Ran, can you open the lid?
Ran, boleh buka kotaknya?
All right.
Baik.
Inspector.
Inspektur.
There's a metal piece in there for fixing the handle in place, right?
Terdapat logam untuk mempertetap posisi drum, bukan?
The mark on her leg that you saw
Tanda yang kau lihat pada kaki korban
was left behind by the metal piece pushed against it.
berasal dari logam yang menekan kakinya.
What?
Apa?
Ms. Yukiko's body was put inside that bass drum case
Jasad Nn. Yukiko diletakkan ke dalam kotak itu
and carried to where she was found.
lalu dibawa ke tempat ia ditemukan.
Isn't that right, Mr. Nakamura?
Benar kan, Pak Nakamura?
Why are you asking me?
Kenapa kau menanyakannya padaku?
You're the only one to ask.
Hanya kau yang bisa ditanyai.
You're the only one who helped put away the musical instruments,
Kau seorang saja yang membantu meletakkan alat musik,
so only you had the chance to put Yukiko's body inside.
jadi kau ada kesempatan untuk lakukan itu.
But when I unlocked the door and went into the dressing room,
Tapi saat aku buka pintu ruang ganti dan masuk,
Yukiko's body was already inside the room.
mayat Yukiko sudah ada di dalam sana.
Ms. Ran saw that too.
Nn. Ran melihatnya juga.
After I finished cleaning up the dressing room,
Aku juga bersama Pak Mouri dan Ran
I was with you and Ms. Ran the whole time.
setelah mengemas barang-barang di ruang ganti.
How on earth would I have time to carry the body to the dressing room?
Bagaimana bisa aku membawa jasadnya ke sana?
Unfortunately, the body that Ran saw
Sayangnya, jasad yang dilihat Ran
was not Ms. Yukiko's body.
bukan jasad sebenar Nn. Yukiko.
What do you mean, Mouri?
Apa maksudmu, Mouri?
Mr. Mouri, I brought what you asked for.
Pak Mouri, aku membawakannya untukmu.
-Isn't that a mannequin? -Yes.
-Bukannya itu boneka? -Ya.
It was in the sports clothing store on the 8th floor.
Ada toko baju olahraga di lantai 8.
As you can see, the left hand has been removed.
Kau lihat, tangan kirinya menghilang.
The hand that Ran saw
Tangan yang dilihat Ran pada waktu itu
was the left hand of this mannequin.
adalah milik boneka ini.
I see.
Begitu.
If it's only the hand of a mannequin, he could carry it in easily.
Tangan boneka mudah dibawa oleh pelakunya.
But back then, I wasn't carrying the hand of a mannequin, was I?
Tadi aku tidak membawa tangan boneka, kan?
Mr. Nakamura.
Pak Nakamura.
Will you please sound your guitar?
Bisakah kau bunyikan gitar kau?
Officer Takagi, will you please sound the guitar?
Petugas Takagi, tolong bunyikan gitarnya.
Yes, sir.
Baik, pak.
Huh? It's out of tune.
Bunyinya tidak selaras.
Mr. Nakamura, you were carrying that guitar
Pak Nakamura, kau membawa gitar
when you entered the dressing room, weren't you?
saat kau memasuki ruang ganti, kan?
The hand of that mannequin was hidden inside your guitar.
Tangan bonekanya disembunyikan di dalam gitar.
After you hid Ms. Yukiko's body into the drum case,
Setelah kau sembunyikan korban ke dalam kotak drum,
you removed the left hand of that mannequin,
kau melepas tangan bonekanya
then put Yukiko's glove onto it,
lalu mengenakan sarung tangan Yukiko padanya
and hid it inside the guitar.
dan menyembunyikannya ke dalam gitar.
You probably used masking tape to stick it on.
Aku kira kau gunakan selotip untuk menempelnya.
When he asked me to sign on the guitar,
Ya, saat dia meminta tanda tanganku,
he really got me.
aku benar-benar terkelabui.
Then, you made Ran wait in the corridor and went into the dressing room,
Kau suruh Ran tunggu di koridor lalu masuk ke dalam ruang ganti
and took out the mannequin's hand that you had hidden in your guitar.
dan mengeluarkan tangan boneka yang disembunyikan di dalam gitar.
You set it up using a cushion and blanket,
Kemudian, kau menggunakan bantal dan selimut
making it look like a person was there,
untuk menjadikan ia seperti orang
and placed the mannequin's hand there.
dan meletakkan tangan boneka di sana.
Then, you made Ran think that Ms. Yukiko was lying on the ground.
Kau membuat Ran pikir bahwa Yukiko ada di sana.
No way.
Oh, tidak.
Leader...
Pimpinan...
After you told Ran to go and get me,
Setelah kau suruh Ran memanggilku,
you carried the drum case containing Ms. Yukiko's body
kau bawa kotak drum yang terletaknya jasad Nn. Yukiko
into the dressing room.
ke dalam ruang ganti.
Then, you took the body out of the case, put the glove on her left hand,
Lalu, kau keluarkan jasadnya, mengenakan sarung tangan
and lay her down under the blanket.
dan membaringkannya di bawah selimut.
After that, you most likely hid the mannequin's hand into your guitar.
Setelah itu, kau sembunyikan tangan boneka di dalam gitar.
But you didn't have time to tune the guitar.
Namun, kau tak sempat mengatur senar gitarnya.
This is the truth.
Inilah kebenarannya.
Leader...
Pimpinan...
Why did you do that?
Kenapa kau lakukan itu?
This band is my life.
Band ini adalah hidupku.
I thought all of you felt the same.
Aku kira kalian juga rasakan hal yang sama.
I'll call you again.
Aku akan meneleponmu lagi.
Okay.
Oke.
Leader.
Pimpinan.
It was rumoured that you and Shota
Katanya kau dan Shota
were going to join the new band that's going to be formed.
bakal bergabung dengan band baru.
Looks like it's true.
Sepertinya itu benar.
That's right. Is there a problem?
Itu benar. Ada masalah?
You were ousted by the previous band you were in
Kau dikeluarkan dari band sebelumnya
because you promoted yourself to a record company, weren't you?
karena kau ingin promosikan dirimu, kan?
You're able to sing now thanks to us. Don't you think so?
Kau masih punya karier nyanyian karena band ini. Kau mengerti?
-What a joke. -What?
-Lucu sekali. -Apa?
You guys made it this far because I joined you.
Kalian masih bisa bertahan karena adanya aku.
Without me, a lowly band like yours would've fallen apart long ago.
Tanpa aku, band seperti kalian ini akan gagal sejak lama.
What did you say?
Apa katamu?
You should be thankful for the fact that you served as a stepping stone
Kau harusnya berterima kasih padaku karena bisa menjadi
for me to make my major debut.
batu loncatan untuk debut aku!
I really believed...
Aku benar-benar yakin...
that everyone else felt the same.
bahwa semua orang merasakannya juga.
I really believed that.
Aku benar-benar percaya.
Mr. Nakamura.
Pak Nakamura.
Please give us the details at the station.
Jelaskan semuanya di kantor.
I'm sorry.
Maafkan aku.
Looks like the beer kicked in after he solved the case.
Sepertinya dia menjadi mabuk setelah kasus diselesaikan.
Don't mention it. No problem at all.
Tidak apa. Tidak ada masalah.
"Mouri's Detective Agency"
"Kantor Detektif Mouri."
Okay, we're here. Don't forget to take your things.
Oke, kita sampai. Jangan lupa bawa barang-barangmu.
Ran, where are the things you bought?
Ran, di mana belanjaanmu?
I forgot about them! The clothes I bought!
Aku lupa! Baju yang aku beli!
I'll head back to Beika Department Store.
Aku akan kembali ke Mall Beika.
-Thank you so much. -Thank you so much.
-Terima kasih banyak. -Terima kasih banyak.